And here we are!
This will be our new home
and workshop
for the next two months,
to be precise.
Um! Mister Collins, this is what
the church provided us?
Indeed they did, and at no cost!
Lewiston isn't far from here
and we'll be able
to secure as much space
as we need to do our work.
Something wrong?
You seem troubled.
This is a charming castle,
if you ask me!
I suppose it has a rustic
appeal, in a sense
but it looks a bit...
♪
- It looks a bit haunted.
- Eh?
Challe! Don't say
such strange things!
[GLEN]
I see. Holly Leaf Castle.
I wondered why they didn't tell
us the name of our new space
now I have my answer.
Holly Leaf Castle?
Do you know something
about this place, Mister Glen?
Not everyone knows the story,
it's quite infamous amongst
those who do.
Fifteen years ago,
the royal family of Millsland
faced an insurrection
started by a branch family,
House Chamber.
It's commonly referred to
as the Chambers Rebellion.
The battle ended in
House Millsland's victory.
And so, House Chamber
and their followers
were put to death.
This castle was associated
with House Chamber.
They killed everyone here?
That's a tragic story,
but is that reason enough
to withhold the name?
It's not like
the place is really...
Oh, but it is! It's haunted!
I bet it's positively brimming
with ghosts!
[screams]
Stop it that's not funny!
I've heard strange tales
but they're just rumors.
Whatever the case,
we're doing this for the sake
of the Holy Beginnings Festival.
Let's not question
the church's generosity.
"Strange tales" he says.
Does sound a bit foreboding,
doesn't it?
Hmm! I'm the Head of Artisans!
I can't afford
to be scared by ghost stories!
Now that we've been chosen
in the selection,
we have to fulfill our promise!
We'll create
beautiful sugar confections
worthy of
the Holy Beginnings Festival!
♪
Huh!
It's spacious enough
but it doesn't seem very clean.
We're supposed to sleep
in this place?
I thought
the Holy Beginnings Festival
was meant to invite good fortune
for the coming year.
If I was good fortune
and I saw this place,
I would turn around
and go the other way.
[ELLIOTT]
All right! All right!
That's enough complaining
for today!
We have all our supplies,
so let's get to work!
[ANNE]
Uh. He's right.
No excuses!
And no being scared, either!
[screams]
[CHALLE] This is likely
the work of House Millsland.
[ANNE]
Challe.
[CHALLE]
Look closely.
They didn't just cut the faces,
swords and decorations
are gone as well.
I think we can assume
what their target was,
the crest of House Chamber.
[ANNE] Then it must
have been everywhere.
[CHALLE] To House Millsland,
the crest of House Chamber
became taboo after they started
the rebellion.
They must have wanted
to eradicate every trace of it.
Uh!
[KING]
I was wondering, Elliott.
What's happened to Bridget?
She said she'd come here later,
so I gave her some money
and asked her
to hire a carriage.
I'm sure she's fine.
[NADIR] That's cold,
coming from her fiance!
Hmm!
[ORLAND] Whatever's happening
with her doesn't concern us now.
Time to move your feet
instead of your mouths.
Hmm! [coughs]
It's just messy, not haunted.
Now, focus, it's time to clean!
[HERBERT]
Silver Sugar Master.
Uh!
♪
No, I'm just imagining things.
[HERBERT]
I'm glad you're here.
[screams]
Hmm! [screams]
- Something wrong?
- I heard one!
- A gh-gh-gh-gh-gh. Ghost!
- Let's calm down.
You know there
aren't any ghosts here.
But there was a voice!
Someone said
"I'm glad you're here," I swear!
Stop. You're hearing things,
that's all.
You may think I'm crazy,
but it's true! I've been cursed!
I've been cursed
by the House Chamber
and they'll haunt me 'til
I'm dead if you don't save me!
Then should I kiss you?
Uh! What did you just say?
A kiss?
Are you still scared?
Uh! No, I'm sorry.
I was just being silly.
[ELLIOTT] Say, Anne!
Can you spare a minute?
It sounds like
I have work to do. Bye, then.
Uh!
It appears that our ghost
leaves footprints.
[ELLIOTT] We're done
bringing the supplies in!
Could you look over the layout
of our workspace?
[ANNE]
Yes, of course!
Hmm!
Why isn't this painting dirty?
Let's leave things here
for today.
Get some rest
and we'll start work tomorrow.
Huh? Sleep in here?
I just feel uneasy somehow.
I know that there are enough
rooms for everyone,
but I don't want to be alone.
Sorry, Mithril Lid Pod,
but can you please stay?
[MITHRIL] Well, it's not
that I mind exactly but--
But what?
I think you should ask
Challe fenn Challe to do this
sort of thing for you,
instead of me.
Really.
Ah! But it's far too
embarrassing
and I'm certain
he'd make fun of me!
You are such a fool!
Keep saying things like that
and your romance will be dead
before it starts!
Love is like a fairy, you know!
It can be born
from anything in any situation!
All right,
I'll ask him for you right now!
- [laughs]
- What? No! Come back here!
I did not agree to that!
I'm trying to repay your favor!
Why are you getting in my way?
Because that wouldn't repay
my favor at all,
- I'm telling you! Stop it!
- Of course it will
- Stay with me!
- [CHALLE] Why are you yelling?
Challe fenn Challe!
Perfect timing!
- Anne wants you to sleep...
- [yells]
I'm sorry, Challe. There's
nothing wrong. Did we wake you?
There's nothing?
And You're certain?
[ANNE]
Um, is there something?
Something violet.
Can't say what.
You're not joking, are you?
What's going on
with this castle?
I knew this place was haunted!
I want to see!
Whether ghosts are the issue
here or not, be careful.
[creaks]
- Hey, come back!
- [Mithril imitates howl]
You can't say all those
scary things
and then just walk away!
How awful.
And whose fault is that, huh?
You should have been bold
and asked him
to sleep with you! Honestly!
Those are completely
different matters!
Now please, will you do
as I asked before?
Just stay here
and sleep with me.
Well, if you insist.
I don't mind.
[birds chirping]
[creaks]
Hmm! Daana, how is
Mister Glen doing today?
Same as before, it seems.
He ate all of his breakfast,
so that's good.
[ANNE]
Good morning, everyone.
[yawns]
Huh! Not you too!
You look just like Orland.
Couldn't sleep?
Uh! Seems like there's something
wrong with the lock to my room.
I kept closing it,
but then the door
would open itself again.
I know what you mean,
my room's the same.
- Mine, too!
- Mine as well.
I heard doors opening
and closing all night long,
so I couldn't sleep a wink.
I wonder
what could be causing this?
Say, that reminds me.
Huh! Since you couldn't sleep,
did any of you happen to see
a violet-colored something
or other last night?
Not that I recall.
Is there something
we should know about?
We have a ghost.
It's been confirmed.
But never fear, my friends
for the magnificent
Mithril Lid Pod
will easily dispose of...
Stop jumping to conclusions.
I never said it was a ghost.
Well, I don't know much
about ghosts,
so I'll leave this to you.
[shouts]
The glory shall be mine alone!
This I vow! You can just
stand back and watch, Challe!
With that matter settled,
let's move on to our work.
First off, I am sure that
our esteemed Head of Artisans
has an idea of how the project
needs to be managed.
Mm-hm.
We have our concept set
but all these confections need
to be a lot larger
than what we made
for the selection.
Remember, we're decorating
the entire church.
So, not only
will the crystals be large,
we'll also need
a tremendous number of them.
Orland and King will be
in charge of kneading.
King will also
handle the coloring.
As for the others,
myself included,
we'll make snow crystals
and handle construction.
Now, as for the schedule
we should...
- Uh?
- [door creaks]
[HUGH] Well, well. What an
interesting workspace this is!
Certainly a creative choice,
coming from the church.
- [ANNE] It's Hugh!
- Hello!
Been quite a while,
Miss Silver Sugar Master.
[ELLIOTT]
An inspection you say?
[HUGH] This is standard
practice every year.
A job performed
by the Silver Sugar Viscount.
It's a commission
from the religious leaders.
It's to ascertain the progress
of the pieces
and ensure that your workmanship
is up to their standard.
That's not the only safety
precaution they take,
by the way.
They also request backup
sugar confections
from the Mercury Workshop.
They hope that you can meet
your obligations
but if you cannot
then the backup confections
will be displayed instead.
Naturally,
you will not be compensated.
Uh! Did you know all this?
That's not good!
Since our school has never
participated in the selection,
it's news to me, too.
No need to worry!
As long as you fulfill your end
of the obligation,
everything will proceed
exactly as planned.
By the way, Anne,
I've heard all
about your exploits!
Pulling these young talents
together, winning the selection,
and even getting Challe back!
And good job, Elliott.
You recognized Anne's
potential right away.
She's a great asset
to the Paige Workshop.
You've got a sharp eye
and dubious morals.
A fine pair indeed.
Your lavish praise
humbles me most painfully.
[HUGH]
I have high hopes.
Well then, I'll go pay
my respects to the master
of the school and be on my way.
Where is Glen's room?
[ELLIOTT]
Come with me.
I forgot to say,
my inspections will always
be unannounced.
I'll appear without warning,
as I did today.
So, don't relax
just because I'm not around.
[ALL]
Hmm!
Now that all that's over with,
are we ready to start work?
[ALL]
Yes!
♪
[ELLIOTT]
All this beautiful silver sugar.
Ah!
Are you helping
or just watching us?
Would you even accept my aid
if I offered it?
Knowing how much work
we have ahead of us,
you shouldn't be scowling at me.
Try asking nicely!
I might be a big help!
A massive hindrance more like.
Can't we have a normal workday?
And a quiet one,
if you don't mind.
I don't need more distractions.
As you wish, then!
♪
[ANNE]
His work is amazing!
He really is
a silver sugar master!
♪
[creaks]
Uh!
♪
[ANNE]
A fairy? Who is that?
How lovely.
Oh, Miss Bridget.
[BRIDGET]
I was told to come, so I came.
I trust you've no objections.
Elliott, let me introduce you.
This is my companion fairy.
I purchased him recently.
My name is Gladus.
It's a pleasure to meet you.
I hope all is well.
What is this, Bridget?
Why did you go
and get another fairy,
especially after
what just occurred.
If you're referring to my Father
taking Challe's wing,
that only happened
because I restrained him.
I won't do the same thing
to this fairy.
I've allowed Gladus his freedom.
That solves this issue,
does it not?
You're doing this to spite
Mister Glen, aren't you?
[gasps]
I'm simply doing what I want,
nothing less and nothing more!
Why are you butting in now?
Usually,
you're so indifferent to me.
Listen, Miss Bridget.
Whatever it is,
I do not want to hear it!
Apologies,
but is there some issue
with my being here,
Miss Bridget?
No issue whatsoever.
I'll be more than happy to tell
father about Gladus myself.
Show me to him.
♪
Hm?
[sighs]
His heart might just give out.
Let's break it to him nice
and easy.
I'll go with you, all right?
This way.
♪
He's a precious stone
just like you,
right, Challe fenn Challe?
Is he an old friend?
That's Challe fenn Challe?
It can't be.
[CHALLE]
Is there a problem?
Pardon. It's nothing.
[ANNE]
You know him?
I've never met him.
It's so strange.
I'm sure that guy was born
from a precious stone,
but I can't figure out
which one at all.
I'm usually really good
at guessing
what objects other fairies
came from too.
I would assume it was opal.
It reflects different colors
in different light.
The picture of ambiguity.
Ambiguity.
You've been dawdling here
for quite some time,
Miss Head of Artisans.
Oh, I'm sorry!
I'll be right there!
I'm afraid Elliot won't be
helping us for a while.
If he's dealing
with family affairs,
he'll be in no state to work.
You saw that?
[huffs]
Whatever happens between them,
we can't allow this
to slow us down.
You're right.
Let's work hard 'til nightfall.
[crickets chirping]
[clinking]
Ah, it's a ghost!
Run away! Ah!
Wait. That's Miss Bridget.
♪
[GLEN] You need
to stop acting like a child!
You brought that fairy in here
just to attract attention
from people
who are supposed to be working!
Now go and return him
to the fairy trader immediately!
What Father said may be true.
Perhaps I just want anyone
at all. It doesn't matter whom.
[ANNE]
Miss Bridget?
Excuse me,
uh, what are you doing?
I'm gazing at the moon.
Is that wrong?
I wasn't trying to complain.
I'm sorry.
[ANNE]
Here.
Is that for me?
I was afraid
you might catch a cold,
dressed like that.
I don't need this. I'm not cold.
- Good night! [chuckles]
- Hold on!
I said I don't need it,
you silly fool.
♪
[creaks]
[ORLAND] Are you meddling
in Bridget's affairs again?
Hm!
[ANNE] I suppose
you could call it that.
You're quite the odd one.
You don't need to trouble
yourself over this mess.
[ANNE] I suppose not,
but what about you?
There's no reason for me
to be bothered with it.
You don't need a reason.
If Bridget looks cold,
does it bother you?
She's a friend. That's normal.
When Bridget came here,
did it bother you
that she brought that fairy.
Did you wonder why?
I'm worried, aren't you?
Right now, our only priority
is making sugar confections
for the festival.
I cannot tolerate distractions.
If you want
to get your work done,
you should do the same.
Everyone's counting on you.
[sighs]
[crickets chirping]
[sword swooshes]
Challe fenn Challe, yes?
That's your name?
What do you want?
Were you expecting someone?
There's something
in this castle,
but it's nature
is still unclear.
Is my nature unclear
to you as well?
♪
I've looked around the castle,
but it feels a bit stuffy.
This tower is nice, though.
A fine breeze.
It's unusual that
you didn't introduce yourself
with your human name.
Do you not have one?
Who is your master?
[CHALLE] No one controls me.
I hold my wing in my own hands.
Yet, you choose to keep company
with humans?
[scoffs]
I can't imagine why.
Enough about me.
To be frank,
you're a bit odd yourself.
You're a precious stone, right?
You should have the ability
to make sharp objects.
So, that must mean you can fight
and yet you were you sold
as a companion fairy.
It's quite the tragedy
but I have no strength at all.
I'll show you.
This is all that I'm capable of.
It isn't much use in a fight.
Your gaze is tightly focused.
Your eyes, dark and deep.
You're straightforward
to a fault,
and you're severe as well.
Since we're fellow fairies,
I had hoped that you
and I could become friends,
but you seem opposed.
Mithril Lid Pod is a fairy,
isn't he?
Daana and Hal, too.
If you're looking
to make some friends,
go ask them.
I don't have much in common
with them.
You and I have
a certain affinity.
And not just because
we're precious stones.
Is that so?
I don't find us alike at all.
You just don't know enough.
[CHALLE]
What is it I don't know?
Do you want me to tell you?
What shall I do?
Perhaps later.
You're not... ready yet.
♪
If you set aside your wariness
and open your heart to me,
then I'll tell you.
But it seems it's far too soon
to hope for that.
You are vigilant,
Challe fenn Challe,
I think that's a good thing.
If you weren't,
you wouldn't survive for long.
♪
From opal.